

Bogdan Sokolovskyi

SENIOR REACT DEVELOPER

sokolovskyi@yahoo.com

Kiev, Ukraine

bogdan-sokolovskyi.github.io

+380980680706

in @linkedin.com/in/sokolovskyi

github.com/bogdan-sokolovskyi

Profile

I have 6+ years of experience working with clients. I have worked on a multitude of web and print-based projects for a range of clients providing Web Design (Prototype, Wireframe, Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma, Zeplin) and Development (JS, ECMAScript 2015-2021, React, Redux, React Hooks, TypeScript, MERN Stack, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, WebSocket, Lodash, jQuery, HighCharts.js, JSON, Rest API, SPA, HTML, PUG, CSS, LESS, SASS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Responsive Layouts, Flexbox, PHP, SQLite, MySQL, NGINX, WordPress, JS Tools (Yarn, npm, Webpack, Gulp, Babel, ESLint), GIT, GitLab, GitHub, Bitbucket, Docker, Bash/ Command Line, Scrum, JIRA, YouTrack, Trello, Redmine, Heroku Cloud, Chrome DevTools, PageSpeed, React/Redux DevTools, Postman, Graceful degradation, Progressive enhancement), Corporate Branding and Graphic Design(UX/UI, Responsive Design, Mobile Design, Cross-Browser Dev).

As a freelance web developer and designer, I collaborate with several web developers in Australia, at the same time maintaining clients in Europe and the USA. I am currently working in Ukraine. I am always available to discuss your project over the phone or via Skype.

Professional Experience

to October 2022

From September 2020 STRONG MIDDLE REACT FRONT-END DEVELOPER

BIMP Kyiv, Ukraine

- Integrations with 1C:CRM, 1C:Enterprise, 1C:Accounting
- Integration of financial and management accounting systems (MAS)
- Development of the application code structure as a SaaS solution based on 1C:CRM
- Technology stack used in our CRM:
 - 1) Design: CRM UX/UI
 - 2) Front-End: React Hooks, Redux advanced pattern(dynamic reducers), TypeScript
 - 3) Back-End: NodeJS

July 2020

From August 2018 to MIDDLE REACT FRONT-END DEVELOPER

FLEXIBLE TECH AND GERCHIK & CO Kyiv, Ukraine

- Development of a personal user account with a flexible interface and flexible modular structure
- Development of risk management tools
- Connecting and configuring charts, graphs, controls into an interactive dashboard. Works with Highcharts Stock
- Creating layout templates on frontend framework React.JS of the CRM system
- Use react-router and advanced elements of the React.JS
- Synchronous stream with Redux, reuse previously created components
- and much more ...

About me



Married (with child)

Ukrainian

Portfolio

Some Works

bogdan-sokolovskyi.github.io

Code Skills

ECMAScript 2015-2021

React, Hooks, Redux

ullet ullet

TypeScript

SOLite

Node IS

HTML / SCSS / WEBPACK / GIT

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Software Skills

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Professional Experience

From April 2018 to August 2018

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

COLORISOFT Kyiv, Ukraine

- Development HTML templates and design integration for the largest E-Learning System Web Portal "WebTutor"
- New adaptive design, create html templates and scripts integration

From 2015 to April 2018

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Design Studio Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- Fixed front end bugs (HTML, CSS, Javascript errors (JQUERY))
- UX tests to test the usability of mobile or websites
- Optimized pages for page speed using Google Page Speed (API) for Apache to obtain higher rankings on Search Engines (SEM)
- Did on site SEO implementations to increase traffic to client websites
- Analyzed traffic and made necessary changes for a better user experience

From 2014 to 2015

JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

Freelance Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- Created and maintained Wordpress based sitess and Templates
- Programmed and debugged in HTML, CSS, and PHP
- Modified photos to be used in websites using Adobe Photoshop
- Assisted in creating the GUI of a real estate application
- Created and executed small programming projects

2013

VOLUNTEER WORK

Web Design & Web Development

- Co-developed a vibrant, secure website using interactive features and SEO best practices to optimize traffic, page views and the user experience (UX).
- Created online promotions, press releases and donation forms that increased cash and food contributions from the local community by 53%.
- Linked online donations to the fundraising database.

2013

STUDENT PROJECTS

Web Design & Web Development

- Developed a website for this fictitious clothing manufacturer that included tools for marketing, crosspromotion and email blasts. The site also included an embedded WordPress blog, plug-ins and a custom banner widget to promote new clothing lines.
- Created a website for this mythical, pizza shop that included a slideshow and collapsible sections on the menu page.
- Created a picture viewing website for this fictitious reality company using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and popular APIs like Facebook, Twitter and Flickr. Added an XML file for captioning.

Language Skills

Ukrainiane

ullet ullet

Native

English



Intermediate 2 (B1)

Education

From July 2020 to September 2020

MERN STACK (MONGODB, EXPRESS.JS, REACT, NODE)

Online and Distance Learning Courses Kyiv, Ukraine

- Node js (32 AH)
- MongoDB, Express.js (20 AH)

From February 2019 to March 2019

REACT WITH TYPESCRIPT & REDUX: DYNAMIC REDUCERS

Online and Distance Learning Courses Kyiv, Ukraine

- JavaScript. TypeScript (14 AH)
- JavaScript. React Hooks (6 AH)
- JavaScript. Dynamic Redux Reducers (6 AH)

From August 2018 to October 2018

From August 2018 to **REACT WITH REDUX TRAINING**

Online and Distance Learning Courses Kyiv, Ukraine

- JavaScript. React and JSX (24 AH)
- JavaScript. React Router and Redux (16 AH)

From July 2013 to September 2013

PHP TRAINING COURSES

Online and Distance Learning Courses Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- PHP. Level 1. Web-development fundamentals (24 AH)
- PHP. Level 2. Web-sites development with MySQL (24 AH)
- PHP. Level 3. Professional development with PHP7 (24 AH)

From April 2013 to May 2013

WORDPRESS CONTENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

Online and Distance Learning Courses Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- WordPress. Level 1. Creating a Website. Content Manager(16 AH)
- Wordpress. Level 2. Creating and maintaining sites with complex structure (16 AH)
- Web-mastering. Configuring Web Servers (24 AH)

From February 2013 to November 2013

JAVASCRIPT TRAINING COURSES

Online and Distance Learning Courses Vinnytsia, Ukraine

- JavaScript. Level 1. Web-Development fundamentals (24 AH)
- JavaScript. Level 2. Extended course (16 AH)
- JavaScript. Level 3a. jQuery Library (16 AH)
- JavaScript. Level 3b. HTML5 API (24 AH)

From November 2012 to February 2013

INTRODUCTION TO WEB DEVELOPMENT

Online and Distance Learning Courses Zhmerinka, Ukraine

- HTML and CSS. Level 1. Web Development using HTML5 & CSS3 - (32 AH)
- HTML and CSS. Level 2. Cross-browser development, usability fundamentals - (32 AH)
- HTML and CSS. Level 3. Advanced methodologies and tools typesetting - (24 AH)

From June 2012 to August 2012

WEB DESIGN

Online and Distance Learning Courses Zhmerinka, Ukraine

- «Principles of design». Express-course (16 AH)
- Development and design of websites (32 AH)